♪Looking in the mirror,
my temples have turned white♪
♪Taking off the hairpins and makeup,
shedding the disguise♪
♪A cold face♪
♪With two lines of tears♪
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
♪The audience offers sincere words♪
♪Perhaps the story could be changed♪
♪The storyteller says♪
♪This mortal world is full of turmoil♪
♪Within sight but beyond reach♪
♪Yet I still don't want to give up♪
♪Don't let the memory be hollowed out♪
♪Don't make me ridiculous♪
♪Some vows turn into smoke
and fade away♪
♪Even the leaves know when autumn comes,
but you don't even know me♪
♪Imprisoned in plight,
yet still full of passion♪
♪I mock this absurd and entangled love♪
♪How can I bear to let go♪
=Whispers of Southern Song=
=Episode 22=
♪Looking in the mirror,
my temples have turned white♪
♪Taking off the hairpins and makeup,
shedding the disguise♪
♪A cold face♪
♪With two lines of tears♪
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
Mr. Rong, sing.
This is probably
your last performance in this world.
Mr. Rong.
Fine. If you don't sing now,
you can sing on your way
to the underworld.
(Shitou, you must survive.)
I once had a brother too.
When I finally found him,
he was already dead.
I dare to come to you
because I know you won't kill me.
Today, I have to protect Rong Xiaonan!
You want to save him?
Shitou.
Hold on.
Xu You'an,
Don't think that putting on an act
with a fake Buddha Head
can help you escape.
Whether it's real or fake
depends on whether
you dare to bet with me.
You should know I've never been
afraid of mutual destruction
or going down together.
Stop!
No.
Go.
For Chun'er.
Shitou.
♪Burned out this life♪
Just go!
♪I ask why♪
♪I yearn for the one who's gone
through heat and cold♪
♪A handful of earth♪
♪The world's last gamble♪
♪Sighing at the late hour♪
♪No one comes to meet me♪
Go to the Rongqing Troupe.
You knew all along that I'm Zhuzi?
When I called you Shitou just now,
you weren't surprised.
Shitou,
why did you hide it from me?
(The current situation is precarious.)
(I thought I'd hide it from you)
(so you wouldn't be too heartbroken.)
(Very well.)
(Meeting you again
has resolved a regret.)
You're still as nagging
as when you were young.
I'm asking you.
When exactly did you find out?
Why didn't you tell me?
I found the button you dropped here.
When I got the button,
too many things happened.
But luckily, you found me.
So you kept your promise.
Governor.
Did you get the explosives planted?
Yes.
Good.
Xu You'an,
you wanted to fool me
with a fake Buddha Head?
I'll blast you to pieces.
What's going on?
Why isn't Miss Jiang back yet?
Is she alright?
I told her to follow secretly.
She'll be fine.
Only by following Xu Fan can we find out
where the Jade Buddha Head is hidden.
But what if she acts impulsively?
She won't.
Chun'er listens to me now.
Today is the Lantern Festival.
Yes.
The full moon brings families together.
Once Chun'er arrives,
we can consider ourselves reunited.
Miss Jiang.
I followed Xu Fan all the way
and found his car parked
at the Rongqing Troupe.
But I saw him come out
not long after he went in.
I was afraid of an ambush,
so I didn't dare go in.
Now we must take back
the Jade Buddha Head from Xu Fan.
If he trades the Jade Buddha Head
for the weapons,
given his nature, he will surely
plunge the people into misery.
But the Rongqing Troupe's front yard
is guarded by soldiers.
I'm afraid we'll be discovered
before we even enter.
I have a plan.
A secret passage in my master's room
leads directly to the backstage
of the front yard
and bypasses the soldiers.
But now Xu Fan will be
even more cautious.
This is our only chance.
So we can't act rashly.
We must plan thoroughly
and strike with one move
to get the Buddha Head back.
♪Looking in the mirror,
my temples have turned white♪
♪Taking off the hairpins and makeup,
shedding the disguise♪
♪A cold face♪
♪With two lines of tears♪
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
♪The audience offers sincere words♪
♪Perhaps the story could be changed♪
♪The storyteller says♪
♪This mortal world is full of turmoil♪
♪Within sight but beyond reach♪
♪Yet I still don't want to give up♪
♪Don't let the memory be hollowed out♪
In my dreams, I've returned here
countless times.
Now that I'm standing here for real,
I still feel as if I'm in a dream
and haven't woken up.
♪Imprisoned in plight,
yet still full of passion♪
♪I mock this absurd and entangled love♪
♪How can I bear to let go♪
Look again now.
Are you still in a dream?
♪Don't make me ridiculous♪
♪Some vows turn into smoke
and fade away♪
♪Even the leaves know when autumn comes,
but you don't even know me♪
I'm taller than you now.
It's ready. Come over here.
♪How can I bear to let go♪
Have you finished?
You do it then.
Go back.
I'll do it.
Press the air bulb.
Is it the air bulb?
It's done?
Hurry.
Did it work?
I think so.
Let's just take another one.
Ready?
Hurry.
It should be done this time.
You have to smile for photos.
Why are you two so tense?
Smile.
You two might as well not smile.
Your smiles look worse than crying.
Just smile.
Smile again.
♪As if it were fate♪
♪Deliberately playing tricks♪
♪We miss each other♪
♪Creating a turbulent drama♪
♪And a bizarre♪
♪Anonymous legend♪
♪The plot twists and turns♪
♪Play out over and over again♪
♪Waiting to be discarded♪
♪And you are like a moth to the flame♪
♪Refuse to submit♪
♪I can't bear to blame you♪
♪There are always too many♪
♪Helpless situations♪
♪Overwhelmed by time♪
♪Even if I have questions♪
♪I harbor desires♪
♪Nowhere to find answers♪
♪People come and go♪
♪I'm still all alone♪
♪Wandering around♪
♪Fortunate to have you with me♪
♪Go through the entanglement♪
♪If longing♪
♪Turns into dust and smoke♪
♪How can I be at ease♪
♪Having walked through prosperous times♪
♪And travelled around the world♪
♪Scars all over me♪
♪If longing never fades♪
♪Burns still hot♪
♪Let it turn into dust and smoke♪
♪After half a lifetime of loneliness♪
♪In the next life♪
♪Entangle with you again♪